

Mathieu**Neron**

Software Engineer

Summary

Software engineer with over 9 years of accumulated professional/internship experience. Versatile, bilingual professional with experience from projects in the aerospace, gaming, consulting, e-signature and finance industry.

Address

3030 Hacienda Street San Mateo, CA 94403 **United States**

Experience

2018-Now **Tableau** Paleau Alto, United States

Senior Software Developer -> LMTS (React, Typescript, C, Qt, C++)

- Improved upon the newly released Object Graph project in the Data pane of Tableau, by adding transition animations, updated tooltips, alphabetical sorting in the graph, etc.
- Contributed to the hybridization of a new Data Preview Area module to showcase the metadata/data grid + embedded relationship editor.
- Participated in a few recruiting interviews and potentially mentoring an intern for this summer, alongside one of my colleague.

Tel

650-505-6213

Mail

mathieu.neron.ing@ gmail.com

> 2016-2018 **Paysafe**

Montréal, Canada

Java Developer (Angular 2+, Typescript, Java 7/8, Spring, Oracle)

- Trailblazed on a new frontend project in Angular 2+ for the new Merchant Portal application.
- Invigorated the Netbanx codebase by fixing bugs, adding unit tests. removing errors/warnings and implementing new features.
- Slashed execution time of frontend tests by a factor of six by switching from PhantomJs to the Nightmage browser automation library.

Web & Git

Linkedin profile Github account

Programming

React

2014-2016 eSignLive by Vasco

Montréal, Canada

Java Developer (Java 7/8, Guava, Spring, AWS, MySQL)

- Implemented and took ownership of features requested by the product manager that were integrated in the eSignLive core application, processing over a billion documents/signatures each year.
- Fixed bugs in the backend codebase. Added API tests, increased code coverage by over 85% on classes with unit tests and applied the campfire rule when possible to insure quality and maintainability.
- Reduced downtime of the Windows document converter by 50%.
- Integrated technologies: Equifax, Twilio, PDFBox, Google Noto Fonts.
- Supported other team members by reducing their time spent investigating for a solution by providing my support and insight whenever needed. Also showcased the backend architecture to multiple new hires.

Personal Skills

2012-2014 Initiative Curiosity ganize Problem Solving Learn/Teach

HTML/CSS

Avanade

Montréal, Canada

- CN (C#/.NET, Sitecore)
 - Redesigned the www.cn.ca website with other Avanade developers using Sitecore and C#/.NET, the main menu being my biggest contribution.
- Hydro-Québec (Javascript, SAPUI5, Infragistics)

Application Developer: Consulted on the following contracts:

 Programmed an internal web-based time spreadsheet application used by Hydro-Quebec managers on their various projects.

OS Preference GNU/Linux **** MacOS **** Windows ***

Internship Experience

2011 Electronic Arts Canada

Burnaby, Canada

Software Engineer Intern (C#/.NET, C++)

- **Implemented** a distributed system in C++/C# managing thousands of simultaneous automated online bots to test the load on SSX snowboard game's server. in collaboration with the Online/UI team.
- **Designed and assembled** a telemetry lookup system in ASP.NET using heat map data to illustrate the activity of players.
- Showcased the online bot tool to fellow interns, which was used afterwards to help present the multiplayer component of the game at Gamescom in Germany.

2010 Autodesk

Montréal, Canada

Software Engineer Intern (C++, Qt, Python)

- **Developed** an animation plug-in inside the Maya software using C++ and Qt with 4 other members of the Games team.
- Wrote and tested mathematical functions in Python for a bloc programming tool used by designers/artists for animation blending, applying what I learned during the internship.

2009 Ubisoft

Québec, Canada

QA Developer Intern (C#/.NET)

- Developed/expanded C# tools which were used by the dev teams of the studio to improve performance/conviviality.
- Maintained and provided support for the tool suite developed by correcting any bug that would arise.

2008 Lockheed Martin

Montréal, Canada

Software Evaluator Intern

- Evaluated a simulation software and insured its quality by writing automated test in Javascript with the TestComplete IDE in addition to writing procedure documentation.
- **Presented** the product in Halifax to clients and helped them understand its inner workings by providing a crash course as well.

Education

2007–2011 **Bachelor** of Computer Engineering

Université de Sherbrooke

Specialization in Software Engineering & Artificial Intelligence

Certifications & Conferences

- Sharepoint 2010 Boot Camp
- Consulting Excellence Foundations (April 2013)
- Codility Certification: https://codility.com/cert/view/cert6AG9RU-X7CHVB5QVHFTSAZ4/
- Angular 2 Professional Certification (December 2016)
- QCon New York 2018 Conference
- Tableau 2018 Boot Camp

French ****
English ****

Interests

Professional: cryptocurrency (did some mining back in 2013-2014), functional programming, machine learning & data science, software architecture, algorithms, design patterns, agile methodologies.

Personal: saxophone, reading, cooking, skiing, running, biking, hiking, traveling

February 19th, 2021

Mathieu Neron